RG 004:077, Manchester Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Manchester Probate Court records
1850-1972
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Manchester District)
27 cubic feet
Record books, 1850-1972, bulk 1850-1920; Probate files, None.
RG004_077
2013-016
Historical Note
Manchester, Hartford County, Town established in May 1823, Parent Town: East Hartford
The Manchester Probate District was constituted June 22, 1850, from the Hartford Probate District. On January 5, 2011 the Manchester Probate District merged with the Andover Probate District to create the Greater Manchester Probate District which serves the municipalities of Andover, Bolton, Columbia, and Manchester.
Town of Manchester, Probate District chronology:
May 1823 - June 21, 1850, Hartford District
June 22, 1850 - January 4, 2011, Manchester District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Greater Manchester District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-40, 1850-1920, and additional bond record books, volumes 47, 63, 75, 89, 103, 121, 136, 151, 166, 1924-1936. There are two volumes numbered 31, one being a bond record book. Contact the probate court to access original record books after Volume 40. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, None.
Arrangement
Record books in accession 2013-016 are numbered consecutively from 1 to 40. There are two volumes numbered 31, one being a bond record book. There are additional bond record books numbered 47, 63, 75, 89, 103, 121, 136, 151, 166.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Manchester
Places:
Manchester (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accession 2013-016, Record books, 1850-1972, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, volumes 1-3, 5, 8, 10, 12, 16, 17, 20, 22, 23, 25, 27, 32, 35, 1850-1916, were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The record books in accession 2013-016 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on October 11, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1850-1972, bulk 1850-1920; 27 cubic feet (50 volumes); 2013-016
  - Records, 1850-1877 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1861-1871 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1869-1878 (Volume 3)
  - Records, 1877-1887 (Volume 4)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1877-1888 (Volume 5)
  - Bonds, 1881-1896 (Volume 6)
  - Records, 1887-1891 (Volume 7)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1882-1891 (Volume 8)
  - Applications, 1884-1902 (Volume 9)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1891-1893 (Volume 10)
  - Orders, 1890-1897 (Volume 11)
  - Wills, inventory, accts & distribution, 1893-1896 (Volume 12)
  - Orders, 1894-1899 (Volume 13)
  - Applications, 1894-1909 (Volume 14)
  - Bonds, 1896-1912 (Volume 15)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1896-1899 (Volume 16)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1898-1901 (Volume 17)
  - Orders, 1898-1904 (Volume 18)
  - Returns, 1902-1922 (Volume 19)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1901-1903 (Volume 20)
  - Orders, 1902-1905 (Volume 21)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1903-1904 (Volume 22)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1905-1906 (Volume 23)
  - Orders, 1905-1908 (Volume 24)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1906-1908 (Volume 25)
  - Orders, 1907-1911 (Volume 26)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1908-1910 (Volume 27)
  - Applications, 1909-1919 (Volume 28)
  - Committal of insane & indigent paupers, 1907-1915 (Volume 29)
  - Commital of insane to private asylums, 1908-1933 (Volume 30)
  - Commital of insane & indigent paupers, 1913-1918 (Volume 31)
  - Bonds, 1912-1924 (Volume 31)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1902-1911 (Volume 32)
  - Orders, 1910-1916 (Volume 33)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1911 (Volume 34)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1911-1916 (Volume 35)
  - Orders, 1912-1915 (Volume 36)
  - Orders, 1913-1917 (Volume 37)
  - Wills, inventory accts & distribution, 1916-1920 (Volume 38)
  - Orders, 1916-1918 (Volume 39)
  - Orders, 1917-1920 (Volume 40)
  - Bonds, 1924-1936 (Volume 47)
  - Bonds, 1936-1945 (Volume 63)
  - Bonds, 1945-1950 (Volume 75)
  - Bonds, 1950-1955 (Volume 89)
  - Bonds, 1955-1959 (Volume 103)
  - Bonds, 1955-1962 (Volume 121)
  - Bonds, 1962-1966 (Volume 136)
  - Bonds, 1966-1970 (Volume 151)
  - Bonds, 1970-1972 (Volume 166)